Inventory of the Iranian Political Opposition Literature collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ittihād-i Mubārizān-i Kumunīst, 1979-1984, undated; 55-56
  - Booklets (Folder 55-56)
    - Esturāh-i burzhvāzī-i millī va mutiraqī, Dānishjuyān havādār ittihād-i mubārāzān kumunīst dar āllemān federāl va berlan gharbī, booklets, 1358 Khordād (1979 May), undated (Folder 56: 1)
    - Kumunīst'hā va junbish-i Dihqānī pass az hil impirīālīstī masālih urzī sar īrān, booklet, 1358 Esfand (1979 March) (Folder 56: 2)
    - Administrative booklets, 1361 (1982) (Folder 56: 3)
      Includes constitution and reports from congress meetings
- Sāzmān-i Mubārāzah Barā-i Ijād-i Junbish-i Mustaghal-i Kārgarī, 1979-1984; 56-57, 84 (Box 56-57, 84: 3)
  Arranged in two groups: Serials and Booklet
  - Serials (Folder 56-57, 84)
    - Junbish-i Dānishjooī, shumārah-i 3, 5-7, 9, 12-14, 16-17, 19-20, journals, 1360 Shahrivar-1363 Ordibihisht (1981 August-1984 April) (Folder 56: 4-6)
    - Junbish-i Kārgarī, (Zurich, Switzerland: s.n.), newspapers, newsletters, and journals, 1358-1360 (1979-1981) (Folder 56-57, 84)
      Weekly publication
      - Shumārah-i 1-17, 1358 Āzar 20-1359 Ordibihisht 15 (1979 December 11-1980 May 5) (Folder 84: 3)
      - Shumārah-i 18-42, 1359 Khordād 1-1360 Ordibihisht 16 (1980 May 22-1981 May 6) (Folder 56: 7-10)
      - Shumārah-i 43-46, 48, 1360 Khordād 1-Mordād 5 (1981 May 22-July 27) (Folder 57: 1)
  - Booklet. Az tānbaku tā mashrutīat va mazhab va islām, (Studio City, Calif.: Havādārān), 1362 (1983) (Folder 57: 2)
- Sāzmān-i Paykār dar Rāh-i Āzādī-i Tabaqah-'i Kārgar, 1968-1985; 57-60 (Box 57-60: 2)
  Arranged in three groups: Serials and Monographs, booklets, and articles, and General
  - Serials (Folder 57-58)
    - 13 Ābān, sāl-i avval, shumārah-i 27-30, photocopies, 1359 (1980) (Folder 57: 3)
    - 16 Āzar, urgān-i dānishjoo, sāl-i avval, shumārah-i 11, newsletter, 1359 Farvardīn 9 (1980 March 29) (Folder 57: 4)
      Special issue for student supporters of Sazman-i Paykar
    - Kārgar, bih pīsh, journals, 1358 Esfand-Tīr (1979 February-June) and undated (Folder 57: 5-6)
    - Nabard-i Bāluch, Ittihād-i Dānishjuyān-i Īrān dar Amrikā, shumārah-i 25-29, newsletters, 1359 Khordād 7-Tīr 4 (1980 May 28-June 25) (Folder 57: 7)
    - Paykār, (Iran?: Sāzmān-i Paykār), photocopies and newspapers, 1358 Ordibihisht-1360 Mehr (1979 April-1981 October) (Folder 57-58)
      - Sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-51, 1358 Ordibihisht-1359 Ordibihisht (1979 April-1980 April) (Folder 57: 8-13)
      - Sāl-i 1, shumārah-i 1-51, 1358 Ordibihisht-1359 Ordibihisht (1979 April-1980 April) (contd.) (Folder 58: 1)
      - Sāl-i 2, shumārah-i 71, 77-78, 95-96, 1359 Tīr 9-Esfand 11 (1980 June 30-1981 March 2) (Folder 58: 2)
      - Sāl-i 3, shumārah-i 105, 110, 114, 118-121, 1360 Ordibihisht 21-Mehr 13 (1981 May 11-October 5) (Folder 58: 3)
    - Paykārgar, sāl-i 1-4, shumārah-i 3-7, (Berlin: s.n.), journals, 1983 November-1985 August (Folder 58: 4)
    - Paykār-i Kurdistān, shumārah-i 1, (Iran?: Sāzmān), journal, 1359 Tir (1980 June) (Folder 58: 5)
      About the liberation of Kurdistan
    - Peykar (English), nos.1-7, 9-10, 12-13, 16, and acknowledgement, (Berkeley, Calif.: UISUS), journals, 1978-1981 (Folder 58: 6-10)
      Excerpts from Paykar (Persian) translated into English and released as a series by the Union of Iranian Students in the United States (UISUS), supporters of Sazman-i Paykar. Issue numbers do not correspond with the original Persian publication.
    - Zindānī-i sīyāsī: āzād bāyad gīrdād, shumārah-i 2-3, and unnumbered, (S.l.: Ittihād-i Dānishjuyān Īrānī dar Amrikā), journals, circa 1360s (1980s) (Folder 58: 11)
      Includes clippings and writings about political prisoners in Iran
  - Monographs, booklets, and articles (Folder 58-60)
    - 'Alīeh-i chand inhiraf: naqdī bar maqālih-yi (masā'il va vazā'yif kununī junbish-i dānishjooī) rufuqā-yi payvand, booklets, undated (Folder 58: 12)
    - Bā chashm-i bāz dar ufuq-i khunīn-i Kurdistān: khātirat-i sarbāz, (S.l.: Sāzmān), monograph, circa 1350s (1970s) (Folder 59: 1)
    - Bīānih-yi paykār 110: mānīfest upurtunīstī-yi rāst, Guruh-i nivisandigān barā-yi tashkīl janāh inqilābī, monograph, undated (Folder 59: 2)
    - Dar Afghanīstān chih mīguzadād?: matn-i kāmil'shudah-'i sukhanrānī-i yik rafīq-i inqilābī-i Afghānī, article photocopy, circa 1359 (1980) (Folder 59: 3)
    - Dar bāreh-yi mas'ālah-i millī, (Sweden: Sāzmān), booklets, 1359 (1980) (Folder 59: 4)
    - Ittihādiāh-'i dīhqanān Marīvan va tajrubah'hā-yi 'ayni-i ān: guftugu'ī bā rafīq shahīd-i Fu'ād Mustafā Sultānī, (Washington, D.C.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), booklets, circa 1980 (Folder 59: 5)
    - Junbish-i dānishjoo va masā'lih-yi dānishjuyān mubārāz, booklets, 1358 Mehr 30 (1979 October 22) (Folder 59: 6)
      Includes related booklet titled Bāz ham dar bāreh-yi junbish-i dānishju'ī va masā'lih-yi "dānishjuyān-i mubārāz", booklet, 1358 Āzar (1979 November)
    - Junbish-i nuvīn kumunīstī-i īrān va sāzmān-i chirīk'hā-yi fadā'ī-i khalq, (S.l.: UISUS), booklets, 1359 Ordibihisht (1980 April) (Folder 59: 7)
    - Khalq-i Bāluch va irtijā' mahālī, Ittihād-i Zahmatkishān-i Bāluchistān, booklet, 1358 Āzar (1979 November) (Folder 59: 8)
    - Khalq-i Kurd chih mīguyand va chih mī khāhand?, (S.l.: Sāzmān), booklet, 1358 Day (1979 December) (Folder 59: 9)
    - Mubārāzāt dīhqānī dar Urumiyah, (Switzerland: Sāzmān), booklet, 1358 Ordibihisht (1979 April) (Folder 59: 10)
    - Mubārāzāt-i zahmatkishān khārij az kishvar, monograph, 1356 (1978) (Folder 59: 11)
    - Mukhtasārī az vaz'īat-i sīyāsī jam'āh junbish-i khalq va tāktīkī kumunīst'hā, booklet, 1357 Esfand (1978 February) (Folder 59: 12)
    - Nabard va mas'ālah-i inshi'ab, Ittihād-i Dānishjuyān īrānī dar Amrikā, monographs, 1359 Tīr (1980 June) (Folder 59: 13)
    - Naqdī bar pīsh bi-su-yi mubārāzāh idī'uluzhīk, zamīn-i vahdat junbish-i kumunīstī (1), Chirīk'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq, (S.l.: Sāzmān-i Paykār), chāp-i 2, monograph, 1358 Farvardīn (1979 March) (Folder 59: 14)
    - Paykār kārgarī: neshrī-yi kārgarī, UISUS, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Havazehai), booklet, 1357 Bahman (1978 January) (Folder 59: 15)
    - Pīrāmun-i mahīyat-i jang-i īrān va 'arāq va bar'khurd'hā-yi inhirāfī bih ān: tī'urīk 1, (S.l.: Sāzmān), monograph, 1359 (1980) (Folder 60: 1)
    - Rifurm yā inqilāb, Arzhang Rahim'zadeh, (S.l.: Sāzmān), monograph, 1361 (1982) (Folder 60: 2)
    - Tahlīlī bar taghīr va tahavvulat-i dārunī-i Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān (52-54), booklet, 1358 Farvardīn (1979 March) (Folder 60: 3)
    - Ti'urīk-sīyāsī 2, (S.l.: Sāzmān), monograph, 1359 (1980) (Folder 60: 4)
  - General (Folder 60)
    - Administrative printed matter, 1357-1359 (1978-1980) (Folder 60: 5)
      Includes group's constitution and circulating proclamations to the student supporters of Paykar
    - Booklets (Folder 60)
      - Published by Razmandīgān-i āzādī-i tabaqeh-yi kārgar, 1358 (1979) (Folder 60: 6)
      - Published by student supporters of Paykar, 1347-1364 (1968-1985), undated (Folder 60: 7-9)
      - Published by other, 1358-1361 (1979-1982) (Folder 60: 10)
    - Newsletters and proclamations, 1357-1361 (1978-1982) (Folder 60: 11)
- Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq (Īrān), 1974-2003, undated; 61-72, 84 (Box 61-72, 84: 11)
  Includes some materials from the National Council of Resistance of Iran, which was founded by the Mujahidin in 1981. Also includes publications from student supporters of the Mujahidin in Europe and the United States (also known as Muslim Student Supporters or M.S.S.).
  Arranged in four groups: Serials, Monographs and booklets, Miscellaneous printed matter, and Videotapes
  - Serials (Folder 61-66)
    - Āmuzāsh'hāi-i dar bāreh-yi sāzmān, anjumān-i dānishjuyān-i musalmān (Amrikā), shumārah-i 1-10, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Mujāhidin), serial monographs, 1358 (1979) (Folder 61: 1-6)
      Each book in the series has a unique title, covering topics relating to democracy, opportunism, and student supporters of the Mujahidin.
    - Āmuzāsh'hāi-i vīzheh-yi javānān, Sāzmān-i Javānān-i Mujāhid, shumārah-i 1-2, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Mujāhidīn), journals, 1359 (1980) (Folder 61: 7)
    - Bulitan-i vīzheh-yi tazāhārat-i 30 Khordād 1365, (S.l.: Ittihādiyah-'i Ānjuman'hā-yi Dānishjuyān-i Musalmān Khārij az Kishvar), newspaper, 1365 Tīr 26 (1986 July 17) (Folder 61: 8)
    - Jangal, neshrī-yi Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, shumārah-i 1-3, journals, 1353 (1974) (Folder 61: 9)
    - Khabar nāmeh, Anjumān-i Dānishjuyān-i Musalman Farānseh, shumārah-i 10, 17-20, 25, 27-29, 33, newsletters, 1365 (1986) (Folder 61: 10)
    - The Lion and the Sun, magazine of the Iranian Resistance, vol. 4, no. 2, (France: s.n.), 1997 September (Folder 61: 11)
    - Majmuāh 'alamiah-hā va muzāgīrī'hā-i sīyāsī-i mujāhidīn-i khalq-i īrān, shumārah-i 1-2, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān), chāp-i 1, books, 1358 Bahman-Esfand (1980 January-Febrauary) (Folder 62: 1-2)
    - "M.S.S. Newsletter", vol. 1, nos. 2-4, 1981 October 19-December 10 (Folder 62: 3)
      In English
    - "M.S.S. Bulletin," vol. 1, nos. 1-5, 1981 October 18-December 26 (Folder 62: 4-5)
      Numbers 1-2 are special issues relating to torture of young prisoners in Iran and an announcement of solidarity with the National Council of Resistance
    - Mujāhid, shumārah-i 5, journal, 1354 Khordād (1975 May) (Folder 62: 6)
    - Neshrī-yi Ittihādiyāh-'i Anjumān'hā-yi Dānishjuyān-i Musalmān Khārij az Kishvar, (S.l.: s.n.), newspapers, 1360-1361, 1365-1368 (1981-1982, 1986-1989) (Folder 62-65)
      - Shumārah-i 2-12, 15-18, 20-26, 1360 Mordād 30-Bahman 23 (1981 August 21-1982 February 16) (Folder 62: 7-10)
      - Shumārah-i 27-50, 52-63, 65, 67-71, 1360 Bahman 30-1365 Ābān 23 (1982 February 19-1986 November 14) (Folder 63: 1-10)
        There is a gap of 4 years between issue number 63 (1982 November 19) and issue number 65 (1986 October 3)
      - Shumārah-i 72-75, 77-81, 83, 88-89, 91-98, 100-117, 1365 Ābān 30-1366 Ābān 29 (1986 November 21-1987 November 20) (Folder 64: 1-9)
      - Shumārah-i 118, 122-129, 131, 144, 147, 150-162, 167-170, 1366 Āzar 6-1368 Ordibihisht 8 (1987 November 27-1989 April 28) (Folder 65: 1-9)
    - NLA Journal, publication of the Public Relations Department of the National Liberation Army of Iran, magazine, 1991 November (Folder 66: 1)
      See also Box 72, Folder 4 for related videotape
    - Porsish va pāsukh 1-2-3: sukhanrānī-i yikī az barādarān-i mujāhid pīrāmun-i bahs-i tabāyin-i jahān dar dānishkadeh pālī tiknīkī, (S.l.: Anjumān-i Dānishjuyān Musalmān), chāp-i 1, book, 1358 Day (1979 December) (Folder 66: 2)
    - Qyām-i kārgar, shumārah-i 1-2, 1355 Āzar-Esfand (1976 November-February) (Folder 66: 3)
    - Tabāyin-i jahān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān), shumārah-i 1-15, journals, 1358 Āzar-Farvardīn (1979 November-1980 March) (Folder 66: 4-9)
      Includes individual issues in addition to published compilations of issues 1-5, 6-10, and 11-15
    - Tahlīl-i junbish-i khalq fahrmān tabrīz, az Sarī āmuzāsh'hāi-i sīyāsī, shumārah-i 2, journal, 1359 (1980) (Folder 66: 10)
    - Vīzheh-yi muhakāmeh sā'adatī, shumārah-i 9-10, newspapers, probably 1359 (1980) (Folder 66: 11)
    - Zimāmdarī-i Kārter: sīyāsat-i jadīd-i impirīālīsm va bāztāb-i ān dar īrān, az Āmuzāsh-i sīyāsī, shumārah-i 1, (S.l.: Intishārat-i sāzmān), serial monograph, 1359 (1980) (Folder 67: 1)
  - Monographs and booklets (Folder 67-71)
    - Ākhar-i khat astahalah va sukhtan tamām 'ayār kārt-i sāltānat, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1366 Ordibihisht (1987 April) (Folder 67: 2)
    - Akhlāq va inzābat-i inqilābī, excerpts from Mojāhid, booklet, 1359 Day (1980 December) (Folder 67: 3)
    - Anān keh shahādat'rā bārguzidand, (Tehran: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1357 (1978) (Folder 67: 4)
    - 'Ashurā, fālsafeh-yi āzādī: sukhanrānī barādar-i mujāhid Musi Khīyābanī beh mināsbat-i 'Ashurā' dar masjad-i dānishgāh-i Tehrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 67: 5)
    - Asnād-i muntasharāh Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Irān, jīld-i avval, (Willmete, Ill.: O.I.M.S.), monograph, 1357 Khordād (1978 May) (Folder 67: 6)
    - Az zindigī-i inqilābīyun dars bigīrīm: yādnāmeh-yi mujāhid shahīd Rizā Rizā'ī, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), monograph, 1353 (1974) (Folder 67: 7)
    - Barnāmeh-yi dulat-i muqat-i jomhourī dimukrātīk islāmī-i īrān, (Long Beach, Calif.: M.S.S.), booklet, 1360 (1981) (Folder 67: 8)
    - Barrasī muhīmtarīn tahavvulat-i sīyāsī az nimāh-i khordād 57 ta nakhust-i vazir-i Bakhtīār, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān), chāp-i 1, booklet and photocopy, 1358 Ābān (1979 October) (Folder 67: 9)
    - Chahārumīn sālgard-i 30 Khordād sar āghāz-i inqilāb-i novīn-i mardum-i īrān, ruz-i "shahādā va zindānīān-i sīyāsī", booklet, circa 1980s (Folder 67: 10)
      Includes mostly signatures of Mujahidin members
    - Chand maqāleh dar bāreh-yi muqāvamat, Manuchehr Hezarkhani (Tehran: Kitāb Tāliqānī), monograph, 1365 (1986) (Folder 67: 11)
    - Chand namuneh az surud'hā-i inqilābī Fālestīnī, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), booklet, 1353 Farvardīn (1974 March) (Folder 67: 12)
    - Chigunah Qur'ān bīyāmuzīm: dīnamīzm-i Qur'ān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1358 Farvardīn (1979 March) (Folder 67: 13)
    - Dānishgāh va 'āmalkard'hāi-i irtijā', Ittihādiyāh-i anjumānhāi-i dānishjuyān-i musalmān dānishgā'hā va madras-i 'ali, booklet, 1359 Bahman (1980 January) (Folder 67: 14)
    - Dars khāndan dar khidmat-i mubārzāh-yi inqilāb va āmuzash va parvarash dar kishvar'hā-i inqilāb, Anjumān-i dānishjuyān-i Musalmān (Amrikā), booklets, 1360 Āzar (1981 December) (Folder 67: 15)
    - Dars'hāi az 17 Shahrivar, booklet, undated (Folder 67: 16)
    - Darsī az surāh-i Anfāl, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), booklets, undated (Folder 67: 17)
    - Darsī az surāh-i Mohammad, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), booklets, 1354 (1975), undated (Folder 68: 1)
    - "Difā'iyah mujāhid shahīd Sa'īd Muhsim va Payāmiyah az Mujāhid Shahīd Muhammad Hanif Mazhad", (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), photocopy, 1358 (1979) (Folder 68: 2)
    - Ehtizār impirāturī-i dulār va tuteh'hā-yi impirīālīstī amrikā, monograph, 1353 Ābān (1974 October) (Folder 68: 3)
    - Falsāfeh-'i sha'a'ir, Musa Khiyabani, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), chāp-i 1, monograph, 1358 Ābān (1979 October) (Folder 68: 4)
    - FarĀzi az tārīkh-i sāzmān-i mujāhidīn-i khalq-i īrān, booklet, 1354 (1975) (Folder 68: 5)
    - Guzārish-i marasam-i chahārum-i khordād va ruz-i itāraz beh impirīālīsm-i amrikā, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 68: 6)
    - Guzārish-i marasam-i ruz-i jahānī-i kārgar, Junbish-i Millī-i Mujāhidīn, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 68: 7)
    - Haqīqī dar bāreh-yi tajāvuz nazāmī amrikā va majārā-yi tabas, (S.l.: Intishārat-i sāzmān), chāp-i 2, monograph, 1359 Tir (1980 June) (Folder 68: 8)
    - Hakimīat-i impirīālīsm va alternātīv inqilābī, (Paris: s.n.), booklet, undated (Folder 68: 9)
    - Hamāvāz bā Mujāhidīn, booklet, 1358 Mehr (1979 September) (Folder 68: 10)
      Includes text of ballads sung by the Mujahidin
    - Hamāseh-'i yik paydarī-i buzurg: sharh-i mukhtasar zindigī-i inqilābī mujāhid shahīd Fatimah Amīnī, monograph, 1359 (1980) (Folder 68: 11)
      Includes a copy in Arabic
    - In Support of the Iranian People's Revolutionary Movement, (Berkeley, Calif.: ISAUS), booklet, 1977 June (Folder 68: 12)
      Includes English translations of speeches and writings of the People's Mujahidin of Iran and the Iranian People's Sacrifice Guerrillas
    - Iqtisād beh zabān-i sadah, Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, monograph and photocopy, 1351 Āzar (1972 October) (Folder 68: 13)
    - Irtijā' chist va murtājī' kīst?, (Tehran: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), chāp-i 2, monographs, 1359 (1980) (Folder 68: 14)
    - Jang-i tajāvuz kārānah-'i rizhīm-i shāh dar Umān: khātirat-i yik ufisar-i irāni dar Dhofar, Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, (Paris: Union des Etudiants Iraniens en France), monograph, 1355 Tīr (1976 June) (Folder 68: 15)
    - Lāleh'hā-yi sorkh kavīr, booklet, 1357 (1978) (Folder 68: 16)
    - Kārnāmeh-yi mujāhid shahid sārgard 'ali mahabi: pīshtāz persānal-i inqilāb-i ārtash, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 68: 17)
    - Majmu'āh-i daw sukhanrānī-i yikī az uzāi sāzmān-i mujāhidīn-i khalq-i īrān dar dānishgāh tarīyat mu'āllim, (S.l.: Anjumān-i dānishjuyān-i musalmān-i komputārī), monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 68: 18)
    - Majmu'āh-i guftār-i "pidar Taliqānī", Mahmoud Taliqani, (Long Beach, Calif.: Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān), chāp-i avval, monograph, 1358 (1979) (Folder 69: 1)
    - Majmu'āh-i maqālāti pirāmun-i jang-i īrān va 'āraq, (Long Beach, Calif.: M.S.S.), booklets, 1359 Mehr (1980 September) (Folder 69: 2)
    - Mardumgarāi-i tuhīdī va mardumgarāi-i mubtazal, (Long Beach, Calif.: M.S.S.), booklet, 1359 Mehr (1980 September) (Folder 69: 3)
    - Masā'il-i had junbish-i mā, (Aden, People's Democratic Republic of Yemen: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1355 Esfand (1976 February) (Folder 69: 4)
    - Milliti'hā va masā'lih-yi khalq-i Kurd dar īrān, Anjumān-i Dānishjuyān-i Musalmān, booklets, 1360 Khordād (1981 May) (Folder 69: 5)
    - Mubārzāh-yi zadd impirīālīstī, (S.l.: Anjumān-i dānishjuyān-i Musalmān-i āllemān gharbī), booklet, undated (Folder 69: 6)
    - Mujāhid: sukhanrānī-i yikī az uzāyi-i sāzmān-i mujāhidīn-i khalq-i īrān, Mohammad S'adani (S.l.: s.n.), booklets, 1358 (1979) (Folder 69: 7)
    - Mujāhid Shahīd Mihdī Rizā'i: Pāsukh-i beh ittihāmat-i akhīr-i rizhīm: nāmeh-i sar goshādeh, photocopy, 1354 (1975) (Folder 69: 8)
    - Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, booklet, 1351 Khordād (1972 May) (Folder 69: 9)
    - Muqāvamat-i hamat-i janibāh, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), monograph, 1353 Khordād (1974 May) (Folder 69: 10)
    - Mururī bar kārnāmeh-i khīyānat bar Bāzārgān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1367 Esfand (1988 February) (Folder 69: 11)
    - Pārtui az ziārat-i 'Ashurā, monographs, 1358-1361 (1979-1982) (Folder 69: 12)
    - Partial List of Iranian Martyrs Executed by the Khomeini Regime during December-June 1981, (Berkeley, Calif.: International Solidarity Front for the Defense of Iranian People's Democratic Rights), monograph, circa 1982 (Folder 69: 13)
    - Payām-i tudih-rahbar-i inqilābī-i novīn-i īrān Massoud Rajavī bā hamutanān-i āzādeh va sharīf-i khārij kishvar dar astāneh-yi panjumīn sālgard-i 30 Khordād ruz-i shahādā va zindānīā-i sīyāsī, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1365 Esfand (1987 February) (Folder 69: 14)
    - Rāh-i inqilāb yā rāh-i Banisadr?, booklet, 1359 (1980) (Folder 69: 15)
    - Rāhnamud'hā-i dar bāreh-yi tashkīl shurāhā-yi vaq'ai dar kār khānjat va muā'sasāt, Junbish-i Millī-i Mujāhidīn baksh-i kārgarī, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monographs, 1358 Mehr (1979 September) (Folder 69: 16)
    - Rāhnamud'hā-i shayvāh-'i tahlīl-i sīyāsī, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), booklets, 1358 (1979) (Folder 70: 1)
    - Rustā va inqilāb-i sefīd: barassī-i sharāyat-i inqilābī rustāi-i īrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), monograph, 1351 Ābān (1972 October) (Folder 70: 2)
    - Sardar dar shi'r-i shā'īran: bakshī az shi'rhā va surudhā-'idar bāreh-yi sardar-i kabīr-i khalq Musā Khīyābanī surudāh shudah ast, (Tehran: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), chāp-i 1, monograph, circa 1982 (Folder 70: 3)
    - Sāzmandihā'i va tāktik'hā, Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, (Springfield, Mont.: Payāme Mujāhid), monograph, 1353 (1974) (Folder 70: 4)
    - Shāh: dushmān-i khalq, dushmān-i mujāhidīn, (S.l.: Intishārat-i ittihādiyah-'i anjumān'hāi dānishjuyān-i musalmān dānishgāh'hā va madras-i 'alī), chāp-i 1, booklet, 1359 Bahman (1980 January) (Folder 70: 5)
    - Shinākht, Mujāhidīn-i Khalq-i Īrān, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Abu'dhār), monograph, 1357 (1978) (Folder 70: 6)
    - Shinākht va barrasī-i shivāh'hā va qānunmandī'hā-yi mubārāzāh-i zad impirīālīstī, Anjumān-i dānishjuyān-i musalmān dānishgāh-i kār, monograph, 1359 (1980) (Folder 70: 7)
    - Si surud-i sorkh, Ism'ail Vafa Yaqma'i, (Tehran: Kitāb Tāliqānī), monograph, 1356 Ordibihisht (1986 April) (Folder 70: 8)
    - Sukhanrānī-i Massoud Rajavī dar dānishgāh-i Tehrān, booklet, undated (Folder 70: 9)
    - Tahavval yā tuteh?, booklet, 1356 (1977) (Folder 70: 10)
    - Takāmil, az Idiuluzhīk, kitāb-i sivvum, monograph, 1357 (1978) (Folder 70: 11)
    - Usul-i makhfikārī, fann-i mubārāzāh bā pulīs, Sāzmān-i Mujāhidīn-i Khalq, (Springfield, Mont.: Nahzat-i Āzādi-i Īrān), chāp-i 2, monograph, 1355 Khordād (1976 May) (Folder 70: 12)
    - Vashikastagī-i tārīkh-i dārk-i khurdāh'burzhvā'i az islām, (Long Beach, Calif.: M.S.S.), monograph, undated (Folder 71: 1)
    - Yāddāshtihā-i az zindān-i Evīn az shikast napazīr, (Memphis, Tenn.: Payāme Mujāhid), booklet, 1351 Ābān (1972 October) (Folder 71: 2)
    - Zagheh nashīnhā, shumārah-i 5 az ānchih tā kānun mantashīr shudah ast, (S.l.: Intishārat-i 12 Mahram), monograph, 1356 (1977) (Folder 71: 3)
    - Zandar masīr-i rahā'i, jīld-i avval, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Sāzmān), chāp-i 2, monograph, 1359 Tīr (1980 June) (Folder 71: 4)
    - Zindeh bigurān-i Evīn, booklet, 1361 Bahman (1982 January) (Folder 71: 5)
    - Zur 'alih 'aqīdeh, (S.l.: Intishārat-i Maddras-i), booklets, 1356 Khordād (1977 July) (Folder 71: 6)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter (Folder 71-72, 84)
    - By subject (Folder 71)
      - Martyrs and martyrdom. (Folder 71: 7-8)
        Includes flyers, magazine, and newspaper publicizing the names of Mujahid martyrs and documentating the torture at Evin prison
      - National Council of Resistance. (Folder 71: 9-10)
        Includes newsletters, correspondence, and brochures, 1984-1997 and undated. Also includes the group's constitution and agenda. In English and Persian
    - By format (Folder 71-72, 84)
      - Booklets, 1351-1367 (1972-1988), undated (Folder 71: 11-14)
        Topics include Massoud Rajavi, Kurdistan, and the Islamic Republic of Iran
      - Broadside, 1979 April 8 (Folder 84: 4)
        Titled "Warning of the People's Crusaders of Iran (Mujahidin-i Khalq-i Iran) to the People's Sacrifice Guerrillas (Chirik'ha-yi Fada'i-i Khalq)." Includes an outline of grievances to the People's Sacrifice Guerrillas and a denouncement of the conflict in Kurdistan and Gunbad
      - Clippings, 2003, undated (Folder 72: 1)
        Includes an article about Maryam Rajavi from the New York Times Magazine titled "The Cult of Rajavi"
      - Interviews and biographies of Mujahidin members, booklets, 1354-1361 (1975-1982) (Folder 72: 2)
      - Maps. 3 maps depicting the locations of battles in Iran involving Mujahidin fighters, 1363 (1984) (Folder 72: 3)
      - Newsletters and proclamations, 1356-1365 (1977-1986) (Folder 72: 4-5)
      - Postcard. Features Ayatollah Taliqani (Folder 72: 6)
      - Press releases (English), Washington D.C., 1991-1992 (Folder 72: 7)
      - Speeches and writings, 1977-1981 (Folder 72: 8)
        English translations of defense tribunals, speeches by Massoud Rajavi, and articles from Mojahid
      - Arabic language materials, 1979-1980; 1996. (Folder 72: 9)
        Includes serial booklets and a report on Maryam Rajavi
  - Videotapes (Folder 72)
    - Parade by the Elite Units of the National Liberation Army of Iran, Reviewed by the Leader of the Iranian Resistance, Mr. Massoud Rajavi, probably 1991 (Folder 72)
      See also Box 65, Folder 10 for related magazine, NLA Journal 1991 November
    - Visit to Norway by Mrs. Maryam Rajavi, the Iranian Resistance's President-elect, 1995 October 25-November 6 (Folder 72)
- Sarbāzān-i Īrān, 1981-1987, undated; 73 (Box 73)
  Arranged in two groups: Serials and Monographs, booklets, and articles
  - Serials (Folder 73)
    - Sangar, (Toronto: Sarbazan-i Iran), newsletters, 1362-1366 (1983-1987) (Folder 73: 1-3)
    - Sarbāz, (Falls Church, Va.: Noor Publishing), journal, 1361 Esfand 24 (1983 March 15) (Folder 73: 4)
  - Monographs, booklets, and articles (Folder 73)